Trump sends this uh Coast Guard team,
the Marines Coast Guard to go and seize
this Venezuelan oil tank where they make
this super cool video. This video looks
so cool on my Facebook feed, bro. It
looks so so badass on my Facebook feed,
bro. It really Look at those Coast Guard
go. This is like Call of Duty. This is
like Call of Duty chopper view, sniper
view, UAV view. This is so cool. We got
the Contra VHS quality for the boomers.
This is so cool. You know, you know,
this is like complete propaganda because
they they they use they basically give
you they give you the UAV view. They
give you like the sniper view. That's
for that's for Ginz to try and convince
Ginz that this is super badass. You've
got the POV like you're in the you're in
Call of Duty or in COD. And then for the
boomers, they put it in the VHS quality
uh to make it look like nostalgic like
old war footage that they've seen when
they were younger, when they were in
their 30s and whatnot. And how do we
know it's like complete? This is theater
because the Houthis in Yemen have like
8K HD footage as they're seizing the uh
the the Israeli tankers that are going
through the Red Sea. The Houthis in
Yemen have like 8D footage from every
conceivable angle as they sees their
tankers. But the US is trying to
convince like boomers and stuff to
support the war. 70% of Americans oppose
war on Venezuela. 88% of Ginz opposes
war on Venezuela. So, they're trying to
put out this propaganda stuff to be
like, "This is so cool, isn't it?" Um,
[laughter]
it's I don't know. It's like they're
giving this Millennial Reich their VHS
footage to try and remind them of their
youth and and make this seem like it
it's all super cool. Bro, this is this
is such an unclassified vibe. Um, Maduro
responded to the seizure of this tanker.
He said they militarily assaulted and
stole a civilian ship, kidnapped its
crew like the Pirates of Caribbean. You
know what's funny about this? Like Trump
spent the last few weeks talking about
Somali. Said Somali need to go back to
Somalia, but we know they don't want to
go back there because there's Somali
pirates and it's a it's a [__] hole
country with the Somali pirates. And
then one week later, he's he's doing uh
US Coast Guard Somali pirate aesthetics
where they're teasing Venezuelan oil
tankers as they threaten to launch war
on Venezuela over narot trafficking, but
they're actually doing Somali
>> Pirates of the Caribbean in real life.
>> Pirates of the uh Caribbean style
seizure of giant tankers. It's it's it's
on Oh, this is all such a meme. It's so
crazy. uh the US uh whatever her name
is, Caroline Levit, she's um through her
somehow someway through the overpowering
force of her 500 Botox injections this
week, she is explaining to Fox News that
they are going to in fact take the oil.
The vessel is undergoing a forfeite
process right now. You notice how they
make it sound super legal? They're like,
"Well, it's it's going through the
forfeit for forfeite process. You know,
this is also legal. The forfeite
process." No, you just went down there
Somali pirate style
Yemen style. They waged a war on Yemen
for months on in, bombed countless
civilians. I was there in Yemen. I saw I
met with the civilians that they were
bombing and they did this under the
guise of protecting the free market in
the Red Sea because US ships were being
stopped in the Red Sea by the Houthis.
So now they're just doing the same thing
here, but they bombed Yemen for months
on end because they did the same thing,
you know. Um Mark Warner, I don't know
who this guy is, probably some lib. He
said, "So they can seize an oil tanker
but not a drug boat." The lib's got a
point. He makes a good point. Why can't
they seize the drug boats if they can
seize a whole tanker? Good point. Um
also, the US announced new sanctions on
Venezuela, on Maduro's nephews and six
Venezuelan shipping companies. So, you
know, it's all legal because there's
they're sanctioning the shipping
companies. So, it's legal now, right?
It's totally normal and legal and not
insane. Uh, US Admiral Hoy has stepped
down. He was the admiral leading US
Southcom, which was overseeing the
Caribbean operations, Venezuela,
Colombia, Trinidad, Tobago, Cuba, so on
and so forth. He has officially stepped
down on December 12th, yesterday. Uh, so
this took place the same day that they
seized. I guess as soon as he stepped
down, they said, "Okay, well, now he's
gone. We can He probably said something
like, "If you seize a ship before I
resigned, I will quit the next day and
it will be even more embarrassing for
you." So, they waited until like the
very minute that he resigned. And then
they went and seized the vessel and made
this made this VHS tape uh stupid video
propaganda video about it. Now I there's
a lot of discussion as to why they are
doing this. Why now? Why are they doing
this? What is going on here? And I want
to bring this point to your attention.
Okay, so this is uh probably the biggest
point of all as to why they're doing
this right now. Venezuela, as you know,
controls the world's largest oil
reserves. They literally make the oil
reserves of Saudi Arabia look like
peanuts. Um 85% of Venezuela's oil
exports right now are in $9 currencies.
Venezuela does not export a lot of oil
because the US has sanctioned them. they
have cut off all possibilities for them
to access the necessary chemicals,
additives, machinery, so on and so forth
to actually
um process their own oil in mass. So the
fear is if Venezuela can process
their own oil in mass, this low-grade
oil that they can uh they can take out
of the ground in their country in very
large quantities, larger quantities than
any country on the earth, and they begin
to export that to countries all across
the world, it is very likely that the
vast majority of that oil will not be
going to the United States. Now, the US
has allowed Chevron to do business
there. They account for 25% of
Venezuela's oil exports on a daily
basis. And Maduro's been very chill with
the idea of giving Chevron and everyone
else more oil, more oil deals. If if
it's fair, if it's transparent, if it's
equal, uh they're not getting ripped off
in Venezuela. He said, "I wish that
Chevron could have a 100-year lease to
do business in our country. I want I
wish Trump would allow that, but it's
the US that is blocking oil companies
from doing substantial business in
Venezuela, not Maduro. You get the idea
here. Um, so if the US continues the
blocking of US companies to do business
in Venezuela, that oil will be going to
other countries. It will be going to
China. It'll be going to who knows
where. It's going to be going to
countries like India who who can do
non-doll trade, right? 80% of
Venezuela's oil exports today are priced
in the pro- yuan. The pro- yuan, not the
pro dollar. You see how this is a fear
for the United States? You understand
that the United States, the first thing
that the United States did when we went
into Baghdad, we said, "All right, we're
going to change some that Saddam was
doing. We're going to put uh all all of
Iraqi oil exports on the petro dollar.
Okay? Hey, we're going to we're going to
add it back to the petro dollar. That
was the first executive order that the
Bush administration signed when they
went into Baghdad. What What did we go
into Libya for? Can anyone remind me?
Oh, yeah. It was because Gaddafi was
working to build a new pan-African
currency, Panaffrican political unity,
Panaffrican economic unity. So Africa
would no longer be subservient to um uh
French uh currencies uh to uh I guess
like uh CFA Franc uh in the case of the
Sahel, uh they would no longer be
subservient to the dollar [snorts] and
that was a big no no. And the US said,
"Gaddafi must go. We came, we saw, we
conquered." Isn't that what Hillary
Clinton said? What is her quote? We
came, we saw, we took out Gaddafi, some
dumb [__] like that. Pokemon go to the
Pokemon went to Libya and destroyed
their country. Now they have slave
markets. Well, think about this. If they
did that because of the threat that
Libya posed, if they did that because of
the threat that Iraq posed, imagine what
they will do to stop Venezuela, the
world's largest oil producer or sorry,
the world's largest oil reserve nation
and what could be the world's largest
oil producer if they are allowed to
sovereign develop in a sovereign manner
what they will do to stop Venezuela from
trading their oil in the proan or doing
um you know Venezuelan
um Venezuelan currency to rupee currency
deals. This is a big no no for the
United States and they will do anything
to stop it. Now the other thing here is
that Venezuela is not a BRICS member. A
lot of people think Venezuela is a BRICS
member but actually the US forced Brazil
under Lula to block Venezuela from
joining as a BRICS member in Kazan
Russia at the uh 2024 bricks summit.
Right? If Venezuela were to become a
BRICS member, that would mean that BRICS
would then control 67%
of the world's oil reserves. If
Venezuela joined BRICS, bricks would
control bricks and bricks partners
nations would would control 67% of the
world's oil reserves. Right now, BRICS
and the partner states control 50% of
the world's oil reserves and output.
With Venezuela, it would be 60 67% clear
majority and of course they'd be more
inclined to help Venezuela obviously
develop the the means to process that
lowgrade oil in that case. Uh but
already China is doing that. John
Kuryaku describes this threat to the US
to the petro dollar and why the US wants
to stop Venezuela from developing their
oil resources, their processing because
of the threat it would pose to the
dollar. Take a listen to what he has to
say here. I think that I think really
what we're seeing here is a slow motion
response or a delayed response to
China's decision five years ago to build
uh an oil refinery in the Caribbean. And
the reason I say that is Venezuela has
very very dirty oil. They have an ocean
of it, but it's very high in sulfur
content and it needs it needs
significant um uh chemical distillation
>> refining
>> refining to not Yeah. And you can't even
use it to turn into gasoline for your
cars. It's mostly made into home heating
oil because it's so dirty and high in
sulfur. Well, until just
>> keep in mind there's a very famous story
of when uh some US cities, impoverished
US cities had like major blackouts
during winter. Venezuela under Ugo
Chavez actually provided energy to those
struggling American families for free.
That's the type of evil state that
Venezuela is. You know, just giving oil
to struggling or giving uh energy to
struggling Americans to help them power
their homes in the dead set of winter
when they had no energy. Five or six
years ago, the only place that you could
refine that oil was in Houston, Texas.
We built refineries that were
specialized just to handle Venezuelan
oil. But then of course we sanctioned
the Venezuelan oil industry. Well, the
Venezuelans didn't then just shut down
their oil industry. The Indians and the
Chinese built new refineries to handle
Venezuelan oil and they ship the oil
there. The Chinese are swimming in
money. And so they decided instead of
shipping the Venezuelan oil all the way
to China, they'll just build the
refinery in the Caribbean, refine it
right there, and ship it out from the
Caribbean. And the United States doesn't
like that. So the bottom line here, I
think, is China.
>> I agree. I mean, there's there's other
reasons. Maria Maria Karina Machado is a
raging Zionist. Um, she called on Israel
to invade and liberate Venezuela from
Maduro. She's the Nobel Peace Prize
winner. Uh, she's a very big liberal.
She wants to put the LGBT values in
Venezuela. Catholic country. um
overwhelming Catholic country. Uh, of
course, you know, Venezuela, it's about
China, it's about the oil, it's about
the petro dollar, it's about all of this
stuff. It's about Venezuela simply
saying that we want to develop in our
own sovereign manner. And if they were
allowed to do that without war being
thrust upon them, it would succeed and
it would then prompt other countries in
Latin America to say, "Hey, Venezuela is
so successful. They are the epicenter of
[snorts] the multi-olar
uh civilization of Latin America that is
showing true sovereign success and we
want to be a part of that. And then
slowly but surely you have other
countries say hey United States we don't
want to live under your we don't want to
have your boot on our neck as well. So
we're going to do what Venezuela did one
by one by one until there's no one left.
Okay, that is what is going on here. And
that is why Venezuela is a threat
because they said, "We're done with the
US Empire. We're going to go in our own
way. We're going to look for our own
partners and we're not going to use the
pro dollar in the process." Before you
leave, I want to say thank you for the
support because after 2 years of being
banned, we are finally back home on
YouTube. So, be sure to subscribe to our
channel and also join as a member on our
channel using the link at the top of the
description. I rely on the generous
support to viewers like yourself to get
the truth out to as many people as
possible. You can also support the show
on locals or give sin go. The mainstream
media and the powers that be are never
going to stop attacking us for bringing
the truth to as many people as we do.
Thank you so much for your support.